When you want to use a database in your application,
عندما تريدون استخدام قاعدة بيانات في تطبيقكم،
first you need to create the database and give it a name.
فإن أول ما تحتاجون إليه إنشاء قاعدة البيانات وتسميتها.
You'll use the create database thread for this.
ستستخدمون سلسلة "create database" لهذا الأمر.
The name you give it here,
الاسم الذي سميتها به هنا،
is the same name you'll use to connect to the database from your code.
هو الاسم نفسه الذي ستستخدمونه في الاتصال بقاعدة البيانات من الكود.
The opposite of create in SQL is drop.
ومقابل "create" في "SQL" هو "drop".
I'm not sure why.
ولا أعلم سبب ذلك.
Maybe database programmers used to be really clumsy.
ربما استخدمها مبرمجوا قاعدة البيانات لتكون صعبة حقًا.
Anyway, the way to remove a data base, is drop database.
على أي حال، إن طريقة إزالة قاعدة بيانات هي "drop database".
And the way to remove a table is drop table.
وطريقة إزالة جدول هي "drop table".
All of these commands have options,
تشتمل كل هذه الأوامر على خيارات.
you can look up in the documentation if you ever need them.
يمكنكم البحث في الوثائق متى وجدت الحاجة إلى ذلك.
When you drop a data base or
عند قيامكم بإسقاط قاعدة بيانات
a table, there's no confirmation, no did you really mean to do that warning.
أو جدول، لا يوجد تأكيد، لم تقصدوا حقًا أن تفعلوا هذا التحذير.
So don't do it, if you don't really mean it.
لذلك لا تفعلوه، إذا لم تقصدوا ذلك بالفعل.
Once you've created a database in psql, you'll want to connect to it.
بمجرد إنشائكم قاعدة بيانات في "psql"، فسترغبون في الاتصال بها.
You can do that using the backslash C command,
يمكنكم ذلك باستخدام الأمر "&lrm;/C"،
followed by the database's name.
بعد اسم قاعدة البيانات.
By the way, you can't drop a database that you're connected to.
على أي حال، يمكنكم إسقاط قاعدة بيانات أنتم على اتصال بها.
Try these commands on your own in your VM using psql.
جرِّبوا هذه الأوامر بأنفسكم في "VM" باستخدام "psql".
First, create a new database called fishies, or whatever you'd like.
أولًا، يمكنكم إنشاء قاعدة بيانات تُسمَّى "fishies" أو أي اسم تريدونه.
Once you've created it,
بمجرد إنشائها،
switch psql's connection over to that database, with \c fishies.
غيروا اتصال "psql" إلى قاعدة البيانات هذه، باستخدام "&lrm;\c fishies".
Then create a table, make one of the columns a text column,
بعد ذلك، أنشئوا جدولًا وسمُّوا أحد الجداول باسم "text column"،
one of the columns a serial column.
وآخر باسم "serial column".
Then try inserting some values with the text column and
ثم حاولوا إدراج بعض القيم في"text column"
selecting some rows from the table.
وحدِّدوا بعض الصفوف من الجدول.
What do you think will happen in the serial column,
ما الذي تعتقدون حدوثه في "serial column"،
when you insert a row that doesn't give it a value?
عند إدراجكم صفًا لا يُعطي قيمة؟
Try it in psql.
جربوا ذلك في "psql".
What was it that actually happened?
ما الذي حدث بالفعل؟
Then after that,
وبعد ذلك،
try finding a description of this behavior in the post SQL documentation.
حاولوا إيجاد وصوف لهذا السلوك في وثائق SQL المنشورة.